Moffat, Abbot Low; Papers apap063
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material, 1929; 1932-1943; 1; 1.30 cubic ft.
  - Press release on Assembly bill extending accident insurance to jockeys, 1942 January 26 (Box 3 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on bill allowing transfer of the Spanish War Refund Account to the General Fund, 1942 January 30 (Box 3 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on budget hearing, 1942 February 2 (Box 3 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on bill creating the Whiteface Mountain Authority, 1942 February 2 (Box 3 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Speaking schedule for hearing on the executive budget, 1942 February 10 (Box 3 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on Governor's message calling for reduced appropriations, 1942 February 12 (Box 3 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on Assembly rent control bill, 1942 February 27 (Box 3 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on Assembly bill allowing the Public Works Department to undertake military construction, 1942 March 2 (Box 3 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - "Summary of Legislative Budget Reductions and Changes", 1942 March 3 (Box 3 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on budget policy of Republican legislators, 1942 March 3 (Box 3 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on Assembly bill calling for construction of an expressway running from New York City to Albany, Buffalo, and the western New York-Pennsylvania state line, 1942 March 13 (Box 3 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on results of talks with the Governor and his advisors concerning quarterly income tax payment and change in the fiscal year, 1942 March 16 (Box 3 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on letter from State Association of Civil Service Employees calling for cost of living increases in salaries, 1942 March 17 (Box 3 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on bills killed and bills reported by the Assembly Ways and Means Committee, 1942 March 17 (Box 3 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on Assembly bill establishing the Post-war Planning and Capital Reserve Fund, 1942 March 20 (Box 3 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on Assembly rent control bill, 1942 March (Box 3 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on letter to Fiorello LaGuardia on bills concerning hiring of teachers from other states and teacher retirement, 1942 April 7 (Box 3 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on recall and recommitment of Assembly rent control bill, 1942 April 15 (Box 3 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on bill allowing quarterly payment of income tax, 1942 April 16 (Box 3 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on the supplemental budget, 1942 April 21 (Box 3 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on need for better military defense of the state, 1942 April 21 (Box 3 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on projected budget surplus appropriations and the estimated operation of the 1942-43 budget, 1942 April 26 (Box 3 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Address on revision of municipal finance laws, the Conference of Mayors, Syracuse, 1942 June 8 (Box 3 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on war's effect on state park revenues, 1942 August 12 (Box 3 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on issuance of the new edition of the Green Book, 1942 August 13 (Box 3 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Address on postwar planning, Rochester Chamber of Commerce and radio station WSAY, Rochester, 1942 November 18 (Box 3 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on bill allowing quarterly payment of income tax and changing the fiscal year, 1943 January 6 (Box 4 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - List of certificates of intent executed since the close of the last legislative session, 1943 January 11 (Box 4 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on Assembly bill allowing quarterly payment of income tax and changing the fiscal year, 1943 January 13 (Box 4 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Letter to Assemblyman [?] Paul Lockwood and press release on cost of gubernatorial inaugurals, 1943 January 13 (Box 4 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Address on Lincoln Day, Utica Republican Club, Utica, 1943 February 12 (Box 4 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
    One copy of the speech has extensive manuscript annotations.
  - Press release on Assembly bill mandating codification and expansion of laws concerning state takeover of unclaimed property, 1943 February 28 (Box 4 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on Assembly bills exempting pay and benefits of military personnel from income tax and allowing five-year carryover of capital losses, 1943 March 7 (Box 4 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on Assembly bill concerning the funding of child care for war workers, 1943 March 9 (Box 4 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on New York City's emergency taxing power, 1943 March 9 (Box 4 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on bill granting a tax exemption to the Metropolitan Opera House, 1943 March 10 (Box 4 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on Assembly bill concerning child care for war workers, 1943 March 22 (Box 4 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on supplemental budget bill, 1943 March 23 (Box 4 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on bipartisan opposition to authorization of additional New York City taxes, 1943 March 25 (Box 4 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on estimated operation of the 1942-43 budget, 1943 March 27 (Box 4 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on State War Council resolution on compilation of emergency war laws, 1943 July 16 (Box 4 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
  - Press release on letter announcing resignation from the Assembly, 1943 August 17 (Box 4 (1-Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Material))
- William F. Bleakley Gubernatorial Campaign Material, 1935-1936; 2; 0.15 cubic ft.
  This series consists of unpublished documents generated in connection with the 1936 gubernatorial campaign of William F. Bleakley, chairman of the New York State Republican Party and former New York State Supreme Court Justice. Included are charts detailing the statewide results of the elections of 1932 and 1936, draft texts of campaign fliers and press releases concerning the fiscal policies of Governor Herbert Lehman, and the text of a speech asserting that New York State residents paid a disproportionately large share of federal taxes.
  - "Election Results in Certain Close Assembly Districts-Democrat Elected", 1935 November 5 (Box 4 (2-William F. Bleakley Gubernatorial Campaign Materia))
  - Bleakley's statement on the relationship between the Executive and the Legislature, 1936 October 7 (Box 4 (2-William F. Bleakley Gubernatorial Campaign Materia))
  - Press release on fiscal statements in Bleakley's speeches, 1936 October 26 (Box 4 (2-William F. Bleakley Gubernatorial Campaign Materia))
  - "Candidates for Member of Assembly", 1936 (Box 4 (2-William F. Bleakley Gubernatorial Campaign Materia))
  - "Candidates for Member of Senate", 1936 (Box 4 (2-William F. Bleakley Gubernatorial Campaign Materia))
  - "General Fund Appropriations, 1936-37, Summary" (Box 4 (2-William F. Bleakley Gubernatorial Campaign Materia))
  - "General Fund Expenditures (Exclusive of Advances for Federal Share of Construction", 1936 (Box 4 (2-William F. Bleakley Gubernatorial Campaign Materia))
  - "General Fund Surplus or Deficit", 1936 (Box 4 (2-William F. Bleakley Gubernatorial Campaign Materia))
  - "Summary of General Fund Appropriations (1936-37)" (Box 4 (2-William F. Bleakley Gubernatorial Campaign Materia))
  - "Disposition of Special Appropriation Bills-Legislature 1936" (Box 4 (2-William F. Bleakley Gubernatorial Campaign Materia))
  - "General Fund: Actual Receipts July 1, 1935 to March 16, 1936 and Estimated Receipts March 17 to June 30, 1936" (Box 4 (2-William F. Bleakley Gubernatorial Campaign Materia))
  - "Comparison of Recommended Appropriations for 1936-1937 with Appropriations for the Fiscal Year 1296-27 (Ten Years Ago)" (Box 4 (2-William F. Bleakley Gubernatorial Campaign Materia))
  - "New State Taxes and Increases in Old State Taxes in Four Years of Governor Lehman", 1936 (Box 4 (2-William F. Bleakley Gubernatorial Campaign Materia))
  - "The Mounting State Debt", 1936 (Box 4 (2-William F. Bleakley Gubernatorial Campaign Materia))
  - "State Debt as of January 1, 1932", 1936 (Box 4 (2-William F. Bleakley Gubernatorial Campaign Materia))
  - "State Debt as of March 16, 1936" (Box 4 (2-William F. Bleakley Gubernatorial Campaign Materia))
  - "Statement Showing State Debt as of September 15, 1936" (Box 4 (2-William F. Bleakley Gubernatorial Campaign Materia))
  - "Allocation of Unemployment Bonds by Governor", 1936 (Box 4 (2-William F. Bleakley Gubernatorial Campaign Materia))
  - "Some Facts Regarding Governor Lehman's So-called 8-point Social Security Bill", 1936 (Box 4 (2-William F. Bleakley Gubernatorial Campaign Materia))
  - "What the Budget of New York State Provides for its 'Unfortunates'-1936-1937" (Box 4 (2-William F. Bleakley Gubernatorial Campaign Materia))
  - Tables listing appropriations under Governors Roosevelt and Lehman, 1936 (Box 4 (2-William F. Bleakley Gubernatorial Campaign Materia))
  - "Statement from the Ways and Means Committee of the Assembly re. Budget Reductions", 1936 (Box 4 (2-William F. Bleakley Gubernatorial Campaign Materia))
  - "Summary of Budget Cuts, Restorations, and the Supplemental Appropriation Bill", 1936 (Box 4 (2-William F. Bleakley Gubernatorial Campaign Materia))
  - "Discrimination Against New York State", 1936 (Box 4 (2-William F. Bleakley Gubernatorial Campaign Materia))
  - "The Governor's Relief Financing as Proposed April 24, 1936, in a Message to the Legislature" (Box 4 (2-William F. Bleakley Gubernatorial Campaign Materia))
  - "Statement of Temporary Notes Issued by the Comptroller", 1936 (Box 4 (2-William F. Bleakley Gubernatorial Campaign Materia))
  - "Savings to Motor Vehicle Owners by Action of Republican Assembly in Refusing to Reimpose Second Additional Cent Tax on Gasoline", 1936 (Box 4 (2-William F. Bleakley Gubernatorial Campaign Materia))
  - "Taxation in New York State Under Lehman and Roosevelt", 1936 (Box 4 (2-William F. Bleakley Gubernatorial Campaign Materia))
  - "Election Results in Certain Close Senatorial Districts-Democrat Elected", 1936 November 3 (Box 4 (2-William F. Bleakley Gubernatorial Campaign Materia))
- Constitutional Convention Material, 1938; 3; 0.05 cubic ft.
  This series contains materials that Moffat created or collected in connection with the 1938 New York State Constitutional Convention. Included are a copy of the printed rule book distributed to delegates, draft copies of proposed amendments concerning state and local finances, and the texts of Republican delegates' informal agreements about state finances. NB: Press releases issued in connection with the convention are contained in Series 1, Press Releases, Speeches, and Reference Materials, 1929-43, and relevant clippings are contained in Subseries 2, Constitutional Convention, 1936-38, in Series 4, Newspaper Clippings, 1934-43.
  - Rules of the 1938 Constitutional Convention (Box 4 (3-Constitutional Convention Material))
  - "Delegates to Constitutional Convention of 1938", 1938 March 16 (Box 4 (3-Constitutional Convention Material))
  - "Suggested List of Subjects which Will Probably Come Before the Committee on State Finances and Revenues", 1938 April 28 (Box 4 (3-Constitutional Convention Material))
  - "Proposed Amendments which Directly or Indirectly Affect State Finances", 1938 (Box 4 (3-Constitutional Convention Material))
  - "Proposed Amendments which Directly or Indirectly Affect State Finances... (Up to and Including May 12, 1938)" (Box 4 (3-Constitutional Convention Material))
  - "Proposed Amendments which Directly or Indirectly Affect State Finances... (Up to and Including May 19, 1938)" (Box 4 (3-Constitutional Convention Material))
  - "Summary of Proposed Amendments before Committee on State Finances and Revenues", 1938 June 2 (Box 4 (3-Constitutional Convention Material))
  - "Proposed Amendments Affecting Local Finances", 1938 June 2 (Box 4 (3-Constitutional Convention Material))
  - "Proposed Amendments Affecting State Finances", 1938 June 2 (Box 4 (3-Constitutional Convention Material))
  - "Memorandum on Points Relating to Local Finances on which Agreement was Reached at Informal Meetings ...", 1938 June 30 (Box 4 (3-Constitutional Convention Material))
  - "Supplemental Memorandum on Points Relating to Local Finances on which Agreement was Reached at Informal Meeting [sic] ...", 1938 July 8 (Box 4 (3-Constitutional Convention Material))
- Newspaper Clippings, 1934-1943; 4; 2.10 cubic ft.
  This series consists of news stories and editorials that Moffat and his legislative staff compiled and kept for reference purposes. Almost all were published in New York State newspapers, but a handful were culled from papers published in Baltimore, Chicago, and other cities. Centering upon state fiscal and political issues, they help to shed light upon Moffat's role in state politics and upon public opinion about state taxation, spending, and social policy.
  - Clerkship Controversy, 1933-1934; 4.1; 0.15 cubic ft.
    This subseries contains news articles and editorials about the 1934 appointment of W. Kingsland Macy as Clerk of the Assembly. Culled from New York City papers, they highlight the disagreements between the Republican Party establishment and the small number of insurgent Republican Assemblymen, Moffat among them, who tried to block Macy's appointment.
    - Clerkship Controversy News Stories, 1933-1934 (Box 4 (4-Newspaper Clippings))
    - Clerkship Controversy Editorials: New York City and Westchester County, 1933-1934 (Box 4 (4-Newspaper Clippings))
    - Clerkship Controversy Editorials: Pro-Macy, 1934 (Box 4 (4-Newspaper Clippings))
    - Clerkship Controversy Editorials: Anti-Macy, 1934 (Box 4 (4-Newspaper Clippings))
    - Clerkship Controversy Editorials: Unsorted, 1934 (Box 4 (4-Newspaper Clippings))
  - Constitutional Convention, 1936-1938; 4.2; 0.20 cubic ft.
    This subseries contains articles, editorials, and political cartoons from the Democrat and Chronicle (Rochester), Knickerbocker News (Albany), Knickerbocker Press (Albany), Times Union(Albany), and other papers detailing the events of and public reaction to the 1938 constitutional convention. Among the proposed amendments detailed are those concerning search and seizure provisions, state and local taxation and bond issuance, welfare and relief provision, the "forever wild" clause, and the rights of organized labor. The clippings also detail delegates' and journalists' opinions about the New Deal and furnish profiles and photographs of numerous delegates.
    - Constitutional Convention, 1936-1937 (Box 5 (4-Newspaper Clippings))
    - Constitutional Convention, 1938 April 1-1938 April 15 (Box 5 (4-Newspaper Clippings))
    - Constitutional Convention, 1938 April 16-1938 April 30 (Box 5 (4-Newspaper Clippings))
    - Constitutional Convention, 1938 May 1-1938 May 15 (Box 5 (4-Newspaper Clippings))
    - Constitutional Convention, 1938 May 16-1938 May 31 (Box 5 (4-Newspaper Clippings))
    - Constitutional Convention, 1938 June 1-1938 June 15 (Box 5 (4-Newspaper Clippings))
    - Constitutional Convention, 1938 June 16-1938 June 30 (Box 5 (4-Newspaper Clippings))
    - Constitutional Convention, 1938 July 1-1938 July 15 (Box 5 (4-Newspaper Clippings))
    - Constitutional Convention, 1938 July 16-1938 July 31 (Box 5 (4-Newspaper Clippings))
    - Constitutional Convention, 1938 August 1-1938 August 15 (Box 5 (4-Newspaper Clippings))
    - Constitutional Convention, 1938 August 16-1938 August 31 (Box 5 (4-Newspaper Clippings))
  - Fiscal and Political Editorials and Stories, 1936; 1938-1943; 4.3; 1.75 cubic ft.
    This subseries consists of one folder of loose clippings. Articles and editorials about state taxes and finance, political cartoons, and issues of the New York State Taxpayer, a publication of the conservative Citizens Public Expenditure Survey, predominate; however, some of the clippings concern President Franklin Delano Roosevelt, the Second World War, and the 1942 gubernatorial campaign of Thomas E. Dewey. The bulk of this subseries consists of editorials and stories about state indebtedness, taxation, and spending that were pasted into scrapbooks. The first scrapbook contains news articles and editorials concerning the work of the Assembly Ways and Means Committee in 1937, but subsequent scrapbooks contain a comprehensive collection of editorials about state finances (1938-40) culled from newspapers published across the state and, in a few instances, across the nation.
    - Miscellaneous Fiscal and Political Clippings, 1936; 1938-1943 (Box 5 (4-Newspaper Clippings))
    - Assembly Ways and Means Committee, 1937-1938 (Box 5 (4-Newspaper Clippings))
    - Assembly Ways and Means Committee Scrapbook (Box 6 (4-Newspaper Clippings))
      1937 Session and January of 1938.
    - Fiscal Editorials, 1938 January-1938 August (Box 7 (4-Newspaper Clippings))
    - Fiscal Editorials, 1939 January-1939 March 15 (Box 7 (4-Newspaper Clippings))
    - Fiscal Editorials, 1939 March 16-1939 May 5 (Box 8 (4-Newspaper Clippings))
    - Fiscal Editorials, 1939 May 5-1939 October 15 (Box 8 (4-Newspaper Clippings))
    - Fiscal Editorials, 1939 October-1940 January (Box 9 (4-Newspaper Clippings))
    - Fiscal Editorials, 1940 February 1-1940 February 15 (Box 9 (4-Newspaper Clippings))
    - Fiscal Editorials, 1940 February 16-1940 March 15 (Box 10 (4-Newspaper Clippings))
- Political Cartoons, 1934?-1939; 5; 0.01 cubic ft.
  This series consists of two original drawings of published political cartoons. The first, Max Plaisted's "Rather a High Price for the Preliminary", was done in pen and ink and was probably drawn early in 1934. It concerns Assembly Republicans' internal disagreements about the appointment of W. Kingsland Macy as Assembly Clerk. The second, Rollin Kirby's "The Climb was Hard Enough Without This!" was done in pencil and colored pencil or pastel and is dated February 18, 1939. It addresses the impact of Governor Herbert Lehman's budget upon the state's taxpayers.
  - Plaisted, "Rather a High Price for the Preliminary", 1934?
  - Kirby, "The Climb was Hard Enough Without This!", 1939